# ASIF AL NOOR

RF Systems Design, System Design (Hardware), PCB Design

roonlafisa@gmail.com | +1-905-783-3906 | https://roonlafisa.github.io

Toronto, Canada (Canadian Citizen)

## **Summary**

I have 8 years of RF system design experience for IoT, cubesats, and rockets. More recently, I had the chance to pick up System Engineering experience when I led the design and development of a full-stack (design to assembly) avionics system for an orbital-scale rocket.

#### **Skills**

System design: End-to-end RF subsystem, Full-stack Standards: IPC-610 (PCB), IPC-620 (Workmanship), hardware subsystem, PCB design, JIRA.

budgets, Ground station, Antenna design, Filter design. RF hardware: RFD900x, Iridium, Globalstar, Quasonix, Safran, CCSDS Receivers, Ublox GPS, JAVAD GPS, LimeSDR, uAvionics Transponder.

RF software: CST, HFSS, ADS, COMSOL, MATLAB tools.

AS50881G (Wiring), MIL-810 (Environmental test).

**Programming:** Python, C, MATLAB, Cube IDE, Linux. PCB design: LT Spice, Altium, Circuit Studio, KiCAD. CAD prototyping: Solidworks, Solidworks electrical. Lab: Oscilloscope, Signal generator, Electrical load, Network Analyzer, Logic analyzer, SMD soldering.

# **Professional History**

#### Senior RF Specialist - SpaceRyde, Toronto ON

Sept 2021 - Present

- · Designed and implemented manufacturing of a rocket avionics system including flight computers, GNC, power management, data networking, RF communications on subsystem and component levels.
- · Architected and commissioned the end-to-end RF system to receive rocket telemetry using legacy COTS design. Scope of responsibilities also included the ground station implementation and operation.
- · Interfaced with regulatory authority (ISED) regarding radio licensing for rocket telemetry spectrum licensing.
- · Designed, assembled and tested PCBs incorporating MCU, serial devices, and other critical components.
- · Spearheaded the development of **test procedures and campaigns** to validate the avionics components.
- · Produced systems requirements and derived requirements for developing avionics components.

#### Intermediate RF Engineer - SMT Research, Vancouver BC

April 2020 - Aug 2021

- · Designed and implemented a battery-less **RF power harvesting** wireless system for structural monitoring.
- · Pioneered custom **RFID passive sensor** tags for remote data logging and pinpointing hidden sensor locations.
- · Installed sensors and DAQs in active construction sites and provided technical support to installation technicians.

#### RF Engineering Consultant - Direct Kinetic Solutions, Texas (Remote)

July 2017 - May 2019

· Produced custom Cubesat EPS and RF system concepts for clients and DOD grant applications.

#### Lead RF Engineer - Helios Wire, Vancouver BC

July 2017 - May 2019

- · Designed, simulated and successfully deployed C, X and S-Band antennas for CubeSat TT&C communication.
- · Conceptualized and modeled an iot gateway to interface between Cubesat in space and IoT tags in the ground.

## **Educational History**

MASc in EE - University of British Columbia, Kelowna BC

Sept 2014 - Oct 2016

· Master Thesis: "A broadband fixed-beam leaky-wave antenna based on transformation electromagnetics."

**BSc in EEE** - Islamic University of Technology, Bangladesh

Jan 2010 - Oct 2013

· Activities: Led the university robotics team during the NASA Lunabotics Annual Competition 2013.

### **Ongoing Personal Projects**

velopment kit using STM32F407 with modular shields. based game on Tx2i Jetson Nano for my toddler.

Embedded Hardware and Firmware: Developing a de- Computer vision: Implementing a gesture detection-